[{"id": "58ab96a986faa38a764be521", "question": "Despite not being the first company to make a minivan, which company introduced the first successful mass-produced minivan in 1983?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf4", "question": "What NFL team did Vince Lombardi coach after leaving the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "The Washington Redskins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36f230ada16518afdc047", "question": "What is the name of the Italian anise-flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Sambuca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ed7b8b5801b8f54a7fb2", "question": "When did the U.S. Postal Service release its first Christmas stamp?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067987ff9c0647b50a804f", "question": "In March, 2016, former politician Radovan Karadzic was sentenced to 40 years in prison for genocide and crimes against humanity committed during what war?", "answer": "Bosnian War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8a92301dd7bf43be5e748", "question": "Who is the patron saint of lost causes?", "answer": "St. Jude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe656ccae7e414034b5aed2", "question": "During the Roman Triumvirate of 42 BCE, what region of the Roman Republic was given to Lepidus?", "answer": "Hispania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61d", "question": "Which US state is home to Petroglyph National Monument?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b808", "question": "What relative does a Russian call \"babushka\"?", "answer": "Grandmother", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc09b948005ec986edcdd", "question": "Who is the fourth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Yeojin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de59fcbed638185eaa15", "question": "Which U.S. state has the longest width east to west?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9d", "question": "Which US President was responsible for the \"Louisiana Purchase\"?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339636", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named John Smith?", "answer": "Pocahontas'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000eda09a72b906b34e3cef", "question": "What is the fattiest human organ?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c6", "question": "What is the thin layer of foam appearing on top of an espresso called?", "answer": "Crema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c10", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the eighth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Locusts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e37", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Up the Mountain to Alm-Uncle\"?", "answer": "Heidi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339794", "question": "In which US state did the Charleston originate?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8841ec223966ae8f881d", "question": "Tamla Records is the former name of which well-established record label?", "answer": "Motown Records", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d4", "question": "What is the atomic number of iodine?", "answer": "53", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a4e220565ad31a57c7c3", "question": "What amusement park was home to America\u2019s first roller coaster?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961f", "question": "What actor played Bill the Butcher in the 2002 movie \"Gangs of New York\"?", "answer": "Daniel Day Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d8", "question": "What element combines with sodium to make ordinary table salt?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90cfc152800b05cac20f0b", "question": "What is the only African nation with Spanish as the official language?", "answer": "Equatorial Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d55952800b05cac20f1d", "question": "During what geological time period did the T-Rex roam the Earth?", "answer": "Cretaceous Period", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b1743a7bb2d29f81593b6f5", "question": "Who wrote the Opera \"The Love for Three Oranges\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b66a", "question": "Which Pac-Man ghost appears first on the arcade game's list?", "answer": "Shadow (Blinky)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75a", "question": "What is the name of the baby depicted on the Sacagawea dollar coin?", "answer": "Pomp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1da", "question": "Before his ears were cut off in 1990 by a political rival, what nation was ruled by dictator Samuel Doe?", "answer": "Liberia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65732ae7e414034b5aed8", "question": "In medieval England, what was used as currency, specifically for rental agreements?", "answer": "Eels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049903cf93664eb104868d", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Tennessee?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8b", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"A Place in the Sun\" based on?", "answer": "An American Tragedy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bb", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", what is Juliet's surname?", "answer": "Capulet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ef9cfe83fe1f2a824c0e", "question": "What year was a Christmas tree first placed in the White House?", "answer": "President Franklin Pierce first placed a Christmas tree in the White House in 1856.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f3", "question": "What is the name the Australian film based on the life of pianist David Helfgott?", "answer": "Shine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7c", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Bad Reputation\" by Joan Jett as its theme song?", "answer": "Freaks and Geeks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14449b0ee8c595b6d39b5", "question": "What is the name of the young adult series featuring Katniss Everdeen?", "answer": "\"The Hunger Games\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35f", "question": "From what bird do we get the meat known as squab?", "answer": "Pigeon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c83", "question": "What forest was home to Robin Hood and his band of Merry Men?", "answer": "Sherwood Forest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e57bfe83fe1f2a824bbf", "question": "Who invented the bidet?", "answer": "Christophe Des Rosiers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c6", "question": "In what country is the holy city of Mecca?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b8", "question": "What TV sitcom opens with the theme \"Making our Dreams Come True\"?", "answer": "Laverne and Shirley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a6", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8f", "question": "What countries share land borders with Cambodia?", "answer": "Thailand, Laos and Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d28", "question": "What children's books character is friends with Christopher Robin?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd8", "question": "What does a howdah sit atop?", "answer": "An elephant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b69930be762b54eb9be9428", "question": "In which US state would you find Twenty Lake?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e72306d333868d34d73a", "question": "How old was Josiah when he became King?", "answer": "8", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e32", "question": "In Greek mythology, whose death in the Aegean Sea, near Samos, was caused by melting wax?", "answer": "Icarus'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa5b473838c5c8a417f2a", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ventriloquist dummies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c848877e98cb977789e1", "question": "Which country has hosted the Wife Carrying World Championships since the competition\u2019s founding in 1992?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72c", "question": "What country does not tolerate outdoor Christmas lights?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7f", "question": "Who was the losing coach in the first Super Bowl, played January 15, 1967?", "answer": "Hank Stram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14040b0ee8c595b6d3998", "question": "What melting food provided the inspiration for Dali's melting clocks?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5dd", "question": "What were barcodes first used for?", "answer": "To label railroad cars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c6c4877e98cb977789bf", "question": "What country has a national park called the \"Valley of Flowers\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d18", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Ciccone?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a89acb8751d53e7d75fb", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11a", "question": "What is the real identity of Aquaman?", "answer": "Arthur Curry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd91", "question": "What Japanese word for \"wave person\" refers to a masterless samurai?", "answer": "Ronin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d7712b42d4a3561a9f0d", "question": "What fast food businessman does Michael Keaton portray in the 2016 film \u201cThe Founder\u201d?", "answer": "Ray Kroc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0dc1afcbed638185eaa0c", "question": "Where can you find a museum dedicated to the history of bread?", "answer": "Ulm, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f05", "question": "What author created the character of Philip Marlowe?", "answer": "Raymond Chandler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb3216e368446ca7bd6840", "question": "Which element has the lowest boiling point?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b46", "question": "For which newspaper does Clark Kent work?", "answer": "The Daily Planet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff0", "question": "Where were fortune cookies invented?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b737", "question": "London's Old Bailey is a what?", "answer": "Criminal court", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a0cf20565ad31a57c79b", "question": "What was the first American war to utilize an early submarine?", "answer": "Revolution War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339345", "question": "What real-life family was the inspiration for the TV show \"Partridge Family\"?", "answer": "The Cowsills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3944c73aa70ea0b70ad9", "question": "Which city hosts the world's largest Passover Seder every year?", "answer": "Kathmandu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a4", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for the inventor of the cyclotron?", "answer": "Lawrencium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a3c83c4039f3d7859290ffb", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed deputy Chester Goode?", "answer": "Dennis Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2d", "question": "Who is Ben Stiller's mother?", "answer": "Anne Meara", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25a", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with the income tax?", "answer": "Sixteenth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afec", "question": "How were presidents John Adams and John Quincy Adams related?", "answer": "They were father and son", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5777c73aa70ea0b70b36", "question": "Which state features a motto that is a rough translation of its name?", "answer": "Texas (\"Tejas,\" means \"allies\" or \"friends.\" The motto of Texas, \"Friendship,\" is thus a loose translation of the state's name.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071cb03745b36be73039cf", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323283bf195a31e15d7391", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation \"Coma Berenices\"?", "answer": "Berenice's Hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfdfef3b668d7dfe168b5b2", "question": "In 1979 what did President Carter apologise to Australia about?", "answer": "Skylab falling on their country", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339880", "question": "In Star Wars, what disguise did Luke and Han wear on the Death Star?", "answer": "Stormtrooper armor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd2", "question": "What TV show did \"The Facts of Life\" spin off from?", "answer": "Diff'rent Strokes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe733a8eec85e375820b223", "question": "In a Nazi concentration camp, a black triangle identified a prisoner as what?", "answer": "Asocial", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede0b96ce05a3942286dba", "question": "Which Bavarian castle did Walt Disney sculpt Cinderella's after?", "answer": "Neuschwanstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c440", "question": "What ape has a name derived from Malay for \"man of the forest\"?", "answer": "Orangutan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6b", "question": "In the game \"Joust\", what animal was your mount?", "answer": "An Ostritch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33d", "question": "How many furlongs to a mile?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded197ea2747c8aff16d34", "question": "Vodka and coffee liqueur make what cocktail?", "answer": "Black Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973c", "question": "Who won an Oscar for the theme song from the movie \"Shaft\"?", "answer": "Isaac Hayes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b44", "question": "What phenomenon appeared the day Mark Twain was born and the day he died?", "answer": "Halley's Comet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c8", "question": "What is a male donkey called?", "answer": "A jack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda5", "question": "What is the name for the arrow-like projectiles fired by a crossbow?", "answer": "Bolts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2af", "question": "According to the title of the film, what is the profession of Ace Ventura?", "answer": "Pet Detective", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3af5ff048f679a45ab30", "question": "What are the three-time periods of the dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic, Jurassic, and Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0db79fcbed638185eaa09", "question": "What is the smallest country by square mileage in North America?", "answer": "St. Kitts & Nevis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c691", "question": "In the human body, what mineral is necessary in the production of hemoglobin?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcf", "question": "What TV show did \"A Different World\" spin off from?", "answer": "The Cosby Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f52", "question": "What photographer had a twenty-year relationship with late author Susan Sontag?", "answer": "Annie Leibovitz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fc0301dd7bf43be5e857", "question": "The name \"Sahara\" is derived from the Arabic word for what?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea33e8ff048f679a45aaf2", "question": "Why is most pollen yellow?", "answer": "To attract bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d23", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"National Velvet\"?", "answer": "Horse racing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d9b3908b8581f80b092c3", "question": "What three gaming consoles did Nintendo release in 2017?", "answer": "Nintendo Switch, New Nintendo 2DS XL, and Super NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd6", "question": "What horse race was first held in 1875 at the Churchill Downs racetrack?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e8f7fe83fe1f2a824be2", "question": "Which monarch appointed Pitt the Younger to the office of prime minister in December 1783?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa550dc73aa70ea0b70b20", "question": "Hastings, England has a distinct May Day festival which is known as what?", "answer": "Jack in the Green", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbebf6ce05a3942286ef6", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Ol' Blue Eyes\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c161", "question": "What is the fear of having to cook called?", "answer": "Mageirocophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab02", "question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14e", "question": "With what nation did the US sign the Paris Peace Accords in 1973?", "answer": "North Vietnam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65f", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Mountain State\"?", "answer": "West Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5db", "question": "When duct tape was first created in 1942, what was it known as?", "answer": "Duck Tape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c154", "question": "A Kamikaze cocktail contains vodka, triple sec and what?", "answer": "Lime juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab45", "question": "What is the capital of Somalia?", "answer": "Mogadishu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7be", "question": "In pool, what color is the 2-ball?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7b", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The African Queen\" set?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacf", "question": "What is the study of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e3a206d333868d34d72e", "question": "During World War I, the territory known as South West Africa was a colony of which country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ce", "question": "In the movie \"Four Weddings and a Funeral\", which character dies?", "answer": "Gareth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc38", "question": "What was the motto of the 1972 Munich Olympic games?", "answer": "The Happy Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c1", "question": "What does Ambidextrous mean?", "answer": "Equally skilled with both hands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76b77eec85e375820b2c3", "question": "What is Ireland\u2019s famous Blarney Stone made of?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b96d", "question": "If you were given a quarter, a cent, 2 dimes and a nickel, how many cents would you have in total?", "answer": "51", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15f", "question": "Who sang the theme to James Bond film \"For Your Eyes Only\"?", "answer": "Sheena Easton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6ec7e83c707845b216f", "question": "Tommy Williams was caught stealing what from a shop in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f2", "question": "Who played Mr. Miyagi in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Pat Morita", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0e", "question": "What is the more common name for an Apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339196", "question": "Which Flinstones character was last to make it onto a Flinstones Vitamin?", "answer": "Betty Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13f", "question": "Which Ferrari model translates literally from Italian as \"red head\"?", "answer": "Testarossa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338943", "question": "What is the name of cartoon character Charlie Brown's dog?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1d", "question": "Besides \"Hey Jude\", what other Beatles song title begins with the word \"Hey\"?", "answer": "Hey Bulldog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96b7c23c87fd04dd15e1c", "question": "What US President tried to set up his daughter with Prince Charles?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be90", "question": "What soft drink line was named after a competitor's unusually tall bottles?", "answer": "Nehi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a985", "question": "What city named its airport after John Lennon?", "answer": "Liverpool", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb56", "question": "What brand of whisky was created in 1939 Queen of England's visit to Canada?", "answer": "Crown Royal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1fe", "question": "What is Pat Benatar's birth name?", "answer": "Patricia Mae Andrzejewski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa8916ce05a3942286ed3", "question": "In the entertainment world, MGM stands for what?", "answer": "Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb1", "question": "Over what part of Captain Robert Jenkins were Britain and Spain at war in 1739?", "answer": "His ear", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e39", "question": "According to Fountains of Wayne, whose mom \"has got it goin' on\"?", "answer": "Stacy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c600", "question": "What is the closest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7a", "question": "What was Jonathan Richman's backing band?", "answer": "The Modern Lovers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e7bcb24f84e0b9f9ffbd", "question": "How many Federal territories are part of Australia?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93c", "question": "Who did Charles Barkley name as \"the one player I'll accept losing to, if I have to lose\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccceaec223966ae8f88a7", "question": "\"American Hustle\" is a fictionalized retelling of what famous sting operation?", "answer": "ABSCAM operation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e563fe83fe1f2a824bbc", "question": "The Islamic calendar is based on which cycle?", "answer": "Lunar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c205", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9dd70e748bb36357acde1", "question": "In the movie \"National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation\", what does Aunt Bethany recite when asked to say grace?", "answer": "The Pledge of Allegiance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d6", "question": "Where did Fonzie, Richie, Potsie and Ralph go to drink sodas and play the jukebox?", "answer": "Arnold's Drive-In", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa39bfc73aa70ea0b70adb", "question": "In which country did the Mambo dance originate?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc8b16de0eb824d4052fe", "question": "Which U.S. state named the cherry as its official state fruit?", "answer": "Utah -- A 1997 school class campaigned on behalf of cherries, an important crop in Utah, and got the nod from state legislators.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a539", "question": "Which US state's highest mountain is Mt. Rainier?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339266", "question": "What is baby Superman called on the planet Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba6f4874c93a3298b215e", "question": "What is Paul Stanley's persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "The Starchild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e9", "question": "What is the only insect that can turn its head like humans?", "answer": "Praying mantis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc53", "question": "Which brewing company originally supplied yeast to produce Marmite?", "answer": "Bass Brewery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e79", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Catch-22\" set?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6653fa5bfecdd737e085d", "question": "Which US president gave the shortest inaugural address?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c878", "question": "What's the world's largest predatory fish?", "answer": "The great white shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a7", "question": "What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a56", "question": "The Nobel Prize for Literature is presented in what Scandinavian city?", "answer": "Stockholm, Sweden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b32354fbf195a31e15d73ad", "question": "Which American comedian was born Benjamin Kubelsky?", "answer": "Jack Benny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b6990e4e762b54eb9be9415", "question": "What standard temperature in Celsius is used by the Normal Temperature and Pressure (NTP) standard?", "answer": "20 C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2d", "question": "In 2007, Jim Carrey starred in a film in which his character was obsessed with what number?", "answer": "23", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976c", "question": "What Will Ferrell movie is about three gun men who start a fraternity and re-live their college years?", "answer": "Old School", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1d", "question": "What author created the land of Alaga\u00ebsia?", "answer": "Christopher Paolini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d5", "question": "Who did the New York Yankees play against in the first televised World Series?", "answer": "The Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf01", "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?", "answer": "Sangria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a127", "question": "Who said \"I always thought losing my virginity was a career move\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a40", "question": "In 2000, the Black Crowes released a live album recorded with what legendary guitar player?", "answer": "Jimmy Page", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70d", "question": "What \"-itis\" is an inflammation of the liver?", "answer": "Hepatitis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e6ba50fb6c85e9e634ff50", "question": "Who composed \"Invitation to the Dance\" in 1819?", "answer": "Carl Maria von Weber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e9", "question": "What colors are the Swiss Flag?", "answer": "Red and White", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf1", "question": "What is the capital of Kyrgyzstan?", "answer": "Bishkek", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb5fec5dad637d903c8828", "question": "Lei Day is a special May Day celebration held in which of America's states?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895e", "question": "What was Cinderella's real name?", "answer": "Ella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b571b4e67df192a942e3367", "question": "FINA is the governing body of what sport?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be47", "question": "What does the abbreviation MPEG stand for in the video and audio compressing format?", "answer": "Moving Picture Experts Group", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d21", "question": "Helen Keller was elected to the Women's Hall of Fame in what year?", "answer": "1965", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feccd5cec223966ae8f88ab", "question": "What bikini-clad seashell hunter does James Bond meet in \"Dr. No\"?", "answer": "Honey Ryder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c6749076251badbead3", "question": "In the U.S., the 1920s were often described by what term?", "answer": "The roaring twenties ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c873", "question": "A tetragon is geometric shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81dced0de9af39e9d4693", "question": "What state elected a former pro wrestler as its governor?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd82396d0de9af39e9d46b0", "question": "The first female U.S. senator was from what state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c862", "question": "What's the common name for the foot ailment also called verrucas?", "answer": "Plantar warts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bc", "question": "What is measured in Ergs?", "answer": "Work", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae92b2574a5ce6b56b8231", "question": "Who wrote the 1950s play \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b1", "question": "What song earned Natalie Cole and Nat King Cole a Grammy Award in 1991?", "answer": "Unforgettable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c852", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the pyloris?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66a0552a821ff76ae8b0a", "question": "A bell was removed from St.Patrick's tomb, 60 years after he died. What is this bell called?", "answer": "The Bell of Testament", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2f", "question": "What year was the Crystal Palace destroyed by fire?", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80a", "question": "What scientist was also the sixth abbot of Brno's Abbey of Saint Thomas?", "answer": "Gregor Mendel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c771", "question": "The Plato Scale is used specifically in the making of what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f0", "question": "Virginia McMath became famous as which actress?", "answer": "Ginger Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c492", "question": "The word \"laser\" stands for what?", "answer": "Light Amplification by Stimulated Emission of Radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1bd", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team finish the design of the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca9", "question": "Al Pacino's satanic character in \"The Devil's Advocate\" is named for what author?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a250", "question": "What year did Ian Gillian replace Ronnie James Dio in Black Sabbath?", "answer": "1982", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc727ec223966ae8f888b", "question": "What is the name of the device used to facilitate dream sharing in the movie \"Inception\"?", "answer": "A Portable Automated Somnacin IntraVenous Device (PASIV)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e37", "question": "Who plays drums on the Beatles track \"Back in the U.S.S.R.\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c207", "question": "Which country were the 1908 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa9", "question": "Who wrote The Angel Doll: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Jerry Bledsoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e2", "question": "What image appears on The Saint's business card?", "answer": "A stick figure with a halo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0c0b469bb8041d07a04c", "question": "What is the official flower of Easter?", "answer": "White Lilly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af39", "question": "What clergyman won a Nobel Peace Prize in 1964?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a949961d1b4d384d5d66e", "question": "In the world of entertainment, how is \"Dana Owens\" more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffa863a3a814d89068c5c", "question": "Winkle is a species of edible what?", "answer": "Sea snails", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f0", "question": "In the 1989 movie \"Batman\", who played the role of the Joker?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940d", "question": "Who directed the 1998 movie \"Out of Sight\"?", "answer": "Steven Soderbergh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ff9393a3a814d89068c52", "question": "Which country's official language is Amharic?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339475", "question": "What was the name of the store Seymour works at in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "SavMart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3599ff048f679a45ab05", "question": "What is the shape of the Milky Way?", "answer": "Spiral", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b954", "question": "In what city is the Kentucky Derby held every year?", "answer": "Louisville", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3236ecbf195a31e15d73c0", "question": "What do you call a boxer who leads with his right?", "answer": "A Southpaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda2", "question": "What last name is shared by Clinton cabinet member Henry and \"The House on Mango Street\" author Sandra?", "answer": "Cisneros", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c4c3fbde8045e48466a1", "question": "What is the function of the skin patches (warts) on a warthog's face?", "answer": "Protection during fights -- Like many animals, male warthogs battle for dominance during mating season.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339796", "question": "Fond of flesh and fava beans, what bad guy was named the American film institutes top villain of all time?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79a", "question": "What fast food chain marketed a meat-scented cologne called \"Flame\" in 2008?", "answer": "Burger King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94a", "question": "What European country ruled Macau until December 20, 1999?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd0", "question": "Which US president walked down the aisle with a three-months pregnant Nancy?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c063", "question": "In 1892, 15-year-old Alonzo \"Lonnie\" Clayton became the youngest winner of which sporting event?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf30", "question": "What is the largest key on a standard computer keyboard?", "answer": "The Space Bar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049bc2cf93664eb10486a1", "question": "What year did Frank Miller publish the comic book series \"300\"?", "answer": "1998", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cf", "question": "The berries of the juniper tree are used to flavour which alcoholic drink?\u00a0", "answer": "Gin\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03a", "question": "Who received the third most popular votes in the 1992 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Ross Perot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958d", "question": "What song did Wayne and Garth listen to on their way to the doughnut shop in the movie \"Wayne's World\"?", "answer": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c07", "question": "Which character in Greek mythology had many heads", "answer": "Lernaean Hydra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b04", "question": "What 2004 movie remake found Denzel Washington playing a role originated by Frank Sinatra in 1962?", "answer": "The Manchurian Candidate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ca", "question": "What San Francisco hill is home to a famous colony of wild parrots?", "answer": "Telegraph Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f3d9ff048f679a45aac4", "question": "Who coined the term dark energy?", "answer": "Michael S. Turner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e338fe83fe1f2a824ba9", "question": "Why was the Japanese capture of Rangoon such a bitter loss for the Allies?", "answer": "As a major seaport, it was an excellent supply point", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73d", "question": "The ailment known as conjunctivitis is also known by what colorful name?", "answer": "Pink eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007821ebd51d85e222ab653", "question": "What was the original title of Auguste Rodin's famous sculpture \"The Thinker\"?", "answer": "Inspired by Dante's\u00a0\"Inferno,\"\u00a0\"The Thinker\" was originally entitled\u00a0\"The Poet\"\u00a0and conceived as a representation of Dante.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d8", "question": "Who sings the theme song from the James Bond film \"Die Another Day\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b521", "question": "How loud is a vuvuzela?", "answer": "127 db", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b6", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was the mother of Queen Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b8", "question": "Which novel is the movie \"Blade Runner\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b554", "question": "In rugby, what is the equivalent of a hockey face-off?", "answer": "Scrum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baeb", "question": "What is the traditional decorative sash worn around the middle of a Japanese kimono called?", "answer": "Obi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915a", "question": "Who is Bugs Bunny's archenemy?", "answer": "Elmer J. Fudd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8ccf594b094db915830a3", "question": "What year was the Academy Award for \u201cBest Animated Feature\u201d added to the list of awards?", "answer": "2002", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdbd5e347d002c297e4e2", "question": "What meteorological significance is traditionally attached to cows lying down?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58be2d788faf425cf37add7e", "question": "The game \"Cities: Skylines\" was developed by which Finnish video game company?", "answer": "Colossal Order", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa3", "question": "What TV family had a road manager named Reuben Kincaid?", "answer": "The Partridge Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3b6bff048f679a45ab35", "question": "\"Bright\u2019s Disease\" affects what part of the body?", "answer": "Kidney", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8dd", "question": "What was Jesse Ventura's wrestling nickname?", "answer": "Jesse \"The Body\" Ventura", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}]